DAVEN CHANG

University of Maryland College Park B.S. in CS/ML

SUMMARY

Passionate about software development and machine learning with a growing interest in Generative AI. Expansive Python skills and experience developed through countless personal projects. Also comfortable with a variety of other programming languages. Collaborative team player with a strong work ethic and a passion for learning and growth.

davenc.dev

dchang1iz@gmail.com

**** +1 703-966-4174

ndaven-c

• Fairfax, Virginia

in daven-chang

SKILLS

Languages:

Python, Java, C, C++, Mojo, HTML, CSS,

Javascript, Arduino.

Technologies: VSCode, Git, Linux, Numpy, Pandas, Ten-

sorflow, Keras, OpenCV, PyTorch, Mediapipe, Threading, Typing, Pygame, RegEx.

EDUCATION

School

Member of Robotics at Maryland, the BigThink AI club, and the Taiwanese American Student Association (TASA). Researcher in the First-Year Innovation and Research Experience (FIRE) program.

 Program

Built cifar-10 classifiers with KNNs and CNNs. Combined NLP and DNN through LSTMs, RNN, and transformers, to predict stock prices from news and market history.

6/2023 - 6/2023 **BWSI - COGWORKS**

Program

Completed pre-requisite course on Autonomous Cognitive Assistants. Learned version control with Git, and advanced knowledge of Python and NLP techniques.

8/2019 - 5/2023 **Oakton High School**

School

Graduated with honors. Participated in track and field, marching band, and concert band. Also joined clubs such as game dev, finance, and business club.

PROJECTS

Hackathon Helping Hands

https://devpost.com/software/helpinghands-myl8ox

Developed a program that utilizes computer vision and the onboard webcam to allow users to move, click, and scroll the mouse remotely using their hands. Used Python, mediapipe, cv2, numpy, pyautogui.

Website davenc.dev

https://davenc.dev

Started work on a personal website as a way of learning HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Learned networking principles such as DNS, IP addresses, and http/tcp as well. Planning to incorporate Node.js and other frameworks

Personal AI-Stuff

https://github.com/daven-c/AI-Stuff

A private repository containing personal AI projects. Projects include classifiers for mnist and cifar, reinforcement models for games such as 2048 and snake, computer vision models such as a hand tracker and iris tracker, and simple regression prediction models.

Personal

https://github.com/daven-c/TheAlJohns

Currently leading a group of friends in the hands-on development of AI/ML projects. Current projects include MNIST GAN for generative, iris tracking for computer vision, and Tetris agent for reinforcement.

EXPERIENCE

2/2023 - Present

Freelance

- Developed first paid website, jewel-inthelotus.com.
- Developed automated discord bots that managed servers, initiated events, created games, and boosted member interaction.
- Built mock games including 2048 and Snake using the pygame library.

8/2021 - 6/2023 **Tuto**i

Fairfax Regional Library

- · Tutored students ranging from K-10 in core subjects including math, science, history, and english.
- · Tutored every Wednesday and Sunday.

COURSEWORK

 Intro to Object Oriented Programming I/II, Data Structures and Algorithms, Intro to Computer Systems, Discrete Structures, Organization of Programming Languages, Algorithms, Calculus I/II, Linear Algebra.